<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CHROLLO BLOG!</title>
    <link>https://0xchrollo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CHROLLO BLOG!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 13:47:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://0xchrollo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unpacking Kovter malware</title>
      <link>https://0xchrollo.github.io/articles/unpacking-kovter-malware/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 20:35:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xchrollo.github.io/articles/unpacking-kovter-malware/</guid>
      <description>Sample:
40050153DCEEC2C8FBB1912F8EEABE449D1E265F0C8198008BE8B34E5403E731 Behaviour analysis this malware uses a highly sophisticated way of unpacking, I&amp;rsquo;ll be demonstrating how to fully unpack it and extract the second stage of it.
let&amp;rsquo;s start by dynamically analysing this sample, fire up ProcMon and execute the sample.
after capturing events with ProcMon, save it to a CSV file and load it to ProcDot, it will look like this.
this is a lot of output!, what we need to focus on are the red colored event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>N00bz CTF-Reverse Engineering-writeups</title>
      <link>https://0xchrollo.github.io/articles/n00bz_ctf_reverse_writeups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 13:47:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xchrollo.github.io/articles/n00bz_ctf_reverse_writeups/</guid>
      <description>Challenge 01- xorxorxor this is an ELF file that asks for the flag when we execute it: let&amp;rsquo;s use IDA to decompile and see how the flag is checked.
as we can see above, it will do the steps:
 read up to 23 characters (length of the flag+1). uses var_4 as a counter that is incremented every time and XORed with a flag character. compares the final string with the string n12a~~~7zV;xSyf&amp;lt;Os!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://0xchrollo.github.io/profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 14:35:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xchrollo.github.io/profile/</guid>
      <description>Hello World!   My name is Motawkkel. Iam from SUDAN.
 A third year college student.
 I Studay at SUST [Electrical Engineering]
    I am currently working as a Cyber Securiy Analysit @ CyberTalents. Mainly skilled at DFIR &amp;amp; Malware Analysis.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BRBBOT - In depth analysis</title>
      <link>https://0xchrollo.github.io/articles/brbbbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 14:35:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0xchrollo.github.io/articles/brbbbot/</guid>
      <description>Sample:
F47060D0F7DE5EE651878EB18DD2D24B5003BDB03EF4F49879F448F05034A21E This is a fairly simple malware sample that can be a great start for beginners in Malware Analysis! As it combines different kinds of techniques and at the same time a simple implementation, So let&amp;rsquo;s start digging into it! 🔥.
Extracting Strings I prefer always to start by viewing the strings as it gives me a general insight on what this sample is doing the information we get from this screenshot is that:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
